Gardner Family papers, 1892-1994
Congregational Library & Archives
- Records of Agnes Gardner Buttrick and Rev. George A. Buttrick, 1924 1993; 1924-1993; 18 Folders
  - Letters from Agnes Gardner Buttrick to Evelyn Gardner, 1951 1976; 1951, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Agnes and Rev. George A. Buttrick's world trip reports, 1951 1952; 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Letters from Agnes and George Buttrick to John Ashworth and Dorothy Luther Gardner, 1956 1969; 1956, 1960, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Rev. G. Robert Buttrick records, 1957 1986; 1957-1986 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Full name was George Robert Buttrick, but most of the material here refers to him as G. Robert Buttrick. His cousin, the donor for this collection, also noted that he was known as Robert throughout his life.
  - Buttrick house search, January 16, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Letters from Agnes and George Buttrick to John Ashworth and Dorothy Luther Gardner, 1970 1973; 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Letters from Agnes and George Buttrick to John Ashworth and Dorothy Luther Gardner, 1979 1985; 1979-1980, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Letters from Agnes Gardner Buttrick to Evelyn Gardner, 1980 1982; 1980-1982, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Letters from Betty and David Buttrick on Agnes Gardner Buttrick, 1987 1989; 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Letters from Agnes and George Buttrick to John Ashworth and Dorothy Luther Gardner, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Records of Annie (Nan) Gardner Glover, Rev. Carl A. Glover and Gloria Diener Glover, 1934 1970; 1934-1943, 1969-1970; 4 Folders
  Biographical / Historical
  Annie Gardner Glover was born on October 17th, 1895. She married Rev. Carl A. Glover and they had one child together, Mary Alnes Glover, in 1922. She died in 1934.
  Rev. Carl A. Glover was born on January 21, 1891. He married Annie Gardner Glover and they had one child together, Mary Alnes Glover, in 1922. He would eventually marry Gloria Diener in 1936. He was a Congregational minister who notably worked at the Park Place Congregational Church of Pawtucket. He was also an author of various religious books. He died on February 12, 1958 in Alameda County, California.
  Gloria Diener was born on March 20, 1902 in Douglas, Oklahoma. She was an educator and author and worked for the First Presbyterian Church of Oklahoma City and also the International Journal of Religious Education in Chicago. She taught in many schools across Illinois, Minnesota, Ohio and California. She married Rev. Carl Glover in 1936. She died in Monterey, California on April 20, 1970.
  This series has a copy of Kopje by Annie (Nan) Garder Glover, records related to her funeral, records from her husband Rev. Carl Glover, and records from Gloria Diener Glover.
  We have five items in our collection written by Rev. Carl A. Glover: "With the Twelve", "Prayer for Christian Services", "The lectern; a book of public prayers", "Victorious suffering", and "Messages from the parables: arranged under the theme The Commonwealth of God"
  "Rev. Carl Archibald Glover obituary". The Times-News. February 26, 1958.
  "Gloria (Diener) Glover". Monterey Peninsula Herald. April 21, 1970.
  - Annie (Nan) Gardner Glover funeral service, 1934-07-05 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Rev. Carl A. Glover's letters and sermon, 1934 1943; 1934, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Gloria Diener Glover records, 1937 1970; 1937, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Kopje by Annie (Nan) Gardner Glover, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Unattributed records, undated; 9 Folders
  This series contains lectures, writings and a letter from the Gardner family's collection that did not indicate owner or author.
  - Riverside, California scenic folder, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Lecture on Tolstoi and lecture on Worms, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Psychology of Religious Experience series, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - A Prayer for Courage by Grace Noll Crowell, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Vocations in changing world, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Letter from Jane to John, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 10 view letter cards of English Lakes, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - The Question of Freemasonry by J. Edward Becker Jr., undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - The Roots of the Reformation outline, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)